In this master class, I'm going to teach
you everything that you need to know
about one of the best concepts in
trading, supply and demand. We are going
to go through all of this and by the end
of the video, you will fully understand
the theory of supply and demand and how
to apply it to find great trades. So,
with that said, let's get in to the
video to briefly explain the theory of
supply and demand. This is the thing
that drives all markets. So, we're
looking at a price scale here and when
demand increases, so this will be our
demand line. we see an increase in the
price of an asset. So let's peg this to
gold for this example. As demand for
gold increases, the price of gold also
increases. This happens because the
supply of gold that's available ready to
trade in the market declines with the
increase in demand. Now why does this
happen? Why does supply fall as demand
rises? Well, it's because of course if
there are lots of people trying to buy
an asset, i.e. there is lots of demand
then there are going to be people buying
that asset taking available supply off
of the market. So that means as demand
increases more assets are bought up and
the supply will decrease. A lower supply
creates higher scarcity and a higher
scarcity demands higher prices because
of course if something is rare versus
something that's not rare the price is
going to be more expensive for the rare
item. Okay, that is simply how it works.
It's very simple format. If we then saw
demand start to slow down, so we saw the
market coming back down in terms of
demand, this would mean people are
selling their assets. Now, if they're
selling their assets, the supply is
going to increase. Okay? And as supply
increases, of course, there are more
readily available units in the market,
which generally means if there is less
scarcity, the price is therefore going
to decrease. So as we see an increase in
demand, we see supply lowering because
the assets are being bought up. When we
see demand decrease, we see more assets
being sold to the market. Therefore, a
lower price comes in due to the fact
that there is now more available supply,
less scarcity, and simply the fact that
if demand's low, pretty much means no
one wants the asset. To bring supply and
demand into our actual trading and our
technical analysis, we do this using
zones. So this here and this here
indicate supply and demand zones. A
demand zone is an area in the market
before a large upward move. So when we
see a sideways bit of price action can
be an individual candle. Show you some
examples in a moment and then a large
push away this creates a demand zone.
When we see the same that kind of
sideways price action of one candle or
maybe more before a large move down this
creates a supply zone. Now to talk about
the theory as to why this happens.
Basically, the reason that we use this
as our demand zone or our supply zone is
because it's showing us where buying and
selling pressure came into the market.
Now, in order for the market to slow
down, kind of recoil and consolidate
before a large push up, that tells us
that this region here where it slowed
down, where it went sideways is where
massive buying orders have been placed.
That is why the market drove higher
because demand kicked in here. supply
was bought up, the price appreciates
because of that increase in demand and
decrease in supply. In the supply
example here, we see the area of
consolidation before a large move down
as essentially a point where new supply
has entered the market. Demand has
declined, more assets have been sold,
readily available to trade. Therefore,
with more supply and lower demand, the
price depreciates. Now the way that we
actually trade these then is to buy
demand zones when the market returns to
them or to sell supply zones when the
market returns to them as well. So in
the case of a demand zone knowing that
this area here is an area where
significant buying is taking place. We
know that this is what we could call a
discount price. Okay traders before saw
this as a very good price to buy this
asset. So they stepped in in mass and we
saw that large drive of momentum. If we
then get up to this point and we start
to slow down, this is telling us that
the price up here is no longer seen as a
discount price to buy and it's no longer
seen as a good price to purchase this
asset. However, we know we have solid
confirmation that this area here was
indeed seen as a good place to buy from
a good price level to purchase this
asset. So the theory is and the concept
is if the market is to return to this
price range again, we are likely to see
a second phase of buying coming in
because this is a discount price region.
If it was a good price to buy before and
now the market's appreciated, you can be
damn sure it's going to be seen by a lot
of people as a good price to buy at
again. The same goes for supply except
this is what we would call a premium
price level. Okay? So, this was a
premium price to sell your assets at.
Whether you are, you know, taking a buy
trade and you're closing out for profit
or you're getting into a short sell
position where you've sold with the
intention of profiting from a down move.
Regardless, it's a premium price to sell
from. And now the market's lower. So, if
you're holding a buy, maybe you don't
want to sell it down here. You'd rather
sell it up here because the higher you
sell it for, the more profit you're
going to get. And if you want to get
into a short position to profit from a
down move, well, you don't want to do it
down here because if you do it from up
here, you're going to get a much better
entry, which means more profits. This
entire range you could actually profit
from instead of just, you know, selling
all the way down here and hoping the
market doesn't return. So therefore,
with this understanding that this is a
premium price to sell from, if the
market is able to return to this level
again, this is going to be a prime place
to place a short order and to profit
therefore from the move down. So that is
how supply and demand zones work. Let's
take a look at those on real charts. So
here we have a market that is in a
downtrend. We're going to identify a
supply zone and show you what it looks
like in the real markets on a real
candlestick chart. So we can see we have
this big push to the downside. This
candle here is an area of consolidation.
Now how do we indicate an area of
consolidation or indecision? Generally
when we are plotting supply and demand
the simple rule is to use an indecision
candle. And I like to use the last
candle before the impulse. Okay? So,
what this means is I don't care what
color the candle is, but I want to see
the last candle before an impulsive move
away. So, if we take a look at this one
here, and we take a look at this one
here, these are indecision candles. They
are indicated as indecision by the fact
they have large wicks and very small
candle bodies. Wicks show rejected
prices. So what we're seeing here with
these wicks is attempts to go higher,
attempts to go lower. And what we see
with a small candle body is pretty much
failure to get far in one direction uh
either way. Okay, we didn't get high, we
didn't get low in this given period of
price action. So this creates an
indecision candle. Now we are looking
for the last indecision candle before an
impulsive move. An impulsive move is a
strong bearish or bullish candle or a
series of strong bearish and bullish
candles. So you can see the candle I've
just marked here. This is a impulsive
candle. It's a large sell candle with no
resistance from the buyers. We see as
well this one after this indecision
candle is a large selling candle with
clear strength from sellers. Okay, no
resistance from buyers. So that is how
we're going to be plotting these in real
time. We want to see the last indecision
candle before the impulse. Last candle
before the impulse is the rule I use.
Now, if you've learned supply and demand
anywhere else before, you might have the
last down candle before the up move, the
last up candle before the down move as a
rule. I don't use that. I use the last
candle before the impulse. The reason I
do this is because it is this candle
here where the selling pressure has
accumulated. Okay? It's not the last up
candle where the selling pressure came
in. This was a strong bullish candle.
It's here. It's the very last candle
before the impulsive move. It's exactly
where the momentum has built up to
create a selling move. It's the selling
pressure. So that is the rule. Last
candle before the impulse is going to be
the one that we use for our supply
zones. Okay. So now to show you this
example, we're going to focus in on this
one. We're going to talk a bit more
about differentiating zones a bit later,
but for now, we've got our supply zone.
To mark a supply zone, we find that last
candle before the impulse, and we want
to mark the high to the low. That
includes the wicks. So our supply zone
would be this. Okay, we've just gone
high to low of this candle. What we
would then expect is for the market to
return to this level and then sell off
from there because we know that that's
where the selling pressure has been
previously. We know this is a premium
price to sell from. So, we would expect
that to take place once again. And this
is going to be a supply zone. So, we're
going to mark it SZ. Why is it supply?
Because it's in a downtrend. It's a
selling move. Okay. Demand is obviously
when we pull back to a buying zone.
Supply is when we pull back to a selling
zone. So this is a supply zone. So what
we could generally expect to see from
here then having plotted that correctly
would be the market to return to here.
We would look to sell there and then we
would profit from a new low being formed
as the market falls. So just as a very
simple example trade, we would have our
entry there, stop above the zone, and
our target down at the low. We're going
to get more into all of this stuff soon,
but first brief example. Here it is. So
there we go. We see the market push into
the supply zone. And what actually
happens here when the supply zone is hit
is a new wave of selling pressure comes
in because of that discount price level.
Because that premium price has been hit,
sellers that sold here before are more
than happy to sell here again. And you
get this nice positive movement straight
down to your target, which is of course
how we make profits from supply and
demand. Now, one very important thing
about supply and demand is that you use
it in line with the overall trend
direction. So we can see this market is
falling. It's creating lower lows and
lower highs. Meaning every low is lower
than the previous one and every high is
lower than the previous one as well. So
what this tells us is that the market is
in what we call a downtrend. Okay? And
in a downtrend, we only want to focus on
selling supply zones. We do not want to
buy demand zones. If we take a look at
this market, we have multiple areas we
could see potentially as demand zones.
But if we were to buy these every time
the market came into them, we would be
destroyed. Okay? All of these areas
would classify as demand zones. But if
you were buying here on the way down,
you're buying here, you're buying here,
you're going to get killed. You're going
to lose loads of trades. So the kind of
sneaky thing about supply and demand is
that supply and demand zones visibly
appear everywhere, but you need to trade
them in context. So in a market that is
moving down, we only want to sell from
supply zones. We do not want to focus on
demand zones. Now, I'm going to give you
a very quick class on market structure
to explain it. Let's go. So, through
this phase of price action just here, we
can see the market is creating higher
highs and higher lows. Okay? So, a
higher high very simply is just a high
like this that's been printed in the
market that's higher than the previous
one. Higher lows again, it's just a low
that's higher than the previous one. So,
as the market is creating higher highs
and higher lows, that puts it in an
uptrend. And that means the only thing
we should focus on doing here is buying
demand zones. We should not sell supply
through here. So this is an uptrend. We
want to buy demand. And that is how we
trade when the market is forming higher
highs and higher lows. At this point, we
see the market shift and it actually
breaks into what we call a lower low.
How do we get this? Well, simply this
low is lower than the previous one.
Therefore, it's a lower low. And through
any phase of price action where we can
clearly define the market is creating
lower lows as well as lower highs, we
want to be selling supply. So if the
lows start to form lower than the
previous ones and if the highs start to
form lower than the previous ones, this
puts us into a downtrend. And during a
downtrend, we want to pretty much ignore
demand zones. And in here, we want to
sell supply. Now, there will be a card
in the top corner of this video. If you
really want further depth on market
structure, lucky for you, I have a full
master class on that as well. Click in
the top right somewhere and that will
take you to it. So, here we have a
market that is creating lower lows and
lower highs. Therefore, what would we
want to do? We would want to sell from
supply zones. Now, an extra little
lesson woven in here. I'm going to use
this sideways candle, this pullback
candle, this kind of indecision candle
in this downward move as supply. As we
can see in this example, there is a
little wick here that extends further on
the next candle. So I would actually use
this candle to mark my range, the blue
one. But I will extend the high of the
zone to the wick that's been created by
the next following candle. Okay? So we
use the high there down to the low here.
That creates our supply zone. So the
idea is then we are going to sell supply
because the market is currently
downtrending creating new lows and new
lower highs consistently. So that would
be pretty much where we get into a trade
from that point onwards. And as we see
the market coming down, of course, we
could then just continue selling supply
zone. So we see again indecision candle,
the market pulls back to supply. That
would be another opportunity to sell.
Okay, so that's the general idea as to
how we focus on a downtrending phase of
price action. Now, as we can see coming
in from this point, we are starting to
push to the upside. Taking a look at the
structure, we actually pushed over this
high. So, we have a high, lower low,
lower high, lower low, lower high, lower
low, lower high, lower low. The market's
pushed up and now it's created a higher
high. So, this actually puts us into an
uptrend. Okay? Meaning, what do we want
to do in uptrends? We want to buy from
demand. So, here's our indecision
candle, our sideways candle before the
impulse. Last candle before the impulse
is what I use for my uh zones. And what
we want to do at this point is buy from
demand. Meaning any supply zones that
form will be ignored. Okay, you can see
that demand zones did form in this move
up. But we ignored them and focused on
selling supply because the market
direction was down. Now that we've
shifted up, we want to focus on buying
demand and we want to ignore supply
because the market direction is up and
we are moving with the market direction
using supply and demand to make our
executions. So in one moment you will
see market returns towards this area of
demand and then we get a tap in and a
push away into new highs. So that is how
we use supply and demand in line with
the trend with a real example there of a
downtrend selling supply and an uptrend
buying demand. So in order to validate a
supply or demand zone, we need to make
sure there is something we call an
imbalance. If there is no imbalance into
a zone, then it's not a zone that we
want to look at. If we take a look at
where I'm drawing these black lines, we
can see just above this candle here,
this blue candle is going to be our
supply zone. Okay, it's the last candle
before this impulse to the downside.
Now, we can see what we have beneath the
low of that candle and then above where
price currently is, there is an
imbalance, right? An imbalance is an
open price range. It's this area here.
Basically, what it is is an area that
hasn't been filled yet with wicks. If
this candle had pushed up and hit that
area, then this would have created what
we call efficiency and removed any
imbalance into that zone. But because we
still have this open price range here,
that means that there is imbalance into
this supply zone. So this would be a
good supply zone to sell from. Okay? And
we would expect when the market comes
back to it, we could happily sell from
this point because that would fill the
imbalance and then the market would be
likely to move lower. Now, you have to
have an imbalance to your supply or
demand zone. Otherwise, it's not really
valid. So, if we take a look above,
we've got here this indecision candle.
This is the last candle before an
impulse to the downside. And just to
clean it up, let's get rid of this.
We'll get rid of this. But the problem
with this zone is there is no imbalance
into it anymore. Right? So, here we have
our supply zone. We have a push away.
The market's pulled back, filled in
balance, and pushed down. So, initially,
if you were looking at this supply and
you wanted to sell it here, that would
have been okay. But now that this has
already been filled, now that there is
no imbalance, this would not be a good
supply zone to try and sell the market
from for two reasons. Number one, the
market probably isn't going to get there
because it's probably going to react
from the area with the imbalance. Number
two, if it does get there, because the
imbalance has already been filled,
there's a high likelihood of it actually
pushing higher, which means it's low
probability and probably isn't going to
give you a good trade. So we need to
trade from supply or demand zones that
still have imbalances. Okay, if we look
in this leg of price movement, there is
no imbalance up here. There's no open
price ranges. Every wick is touching
previous wicks, right? So we have this
wick pushed up, touched this wick, we
pull back down, we have these wicks
being filled by these wicks, but then we
have a push down and we have a gap here
where the wick is not meeting the wick.
So that is basically going to create our
imbalance, making this the high
probability point to sell from. And to
show you that in action, that's the kind
of movement we would expect, a fill of
the imbalance and a push to the
downside. And a rule that goes alongside
that is of course that a zone is only
really good on its first tap in. Okay?
So here we of course had the first tap
in at this point. So we created supply,
pushed down, pulled back, and then sold
off. However, if the market was to come
back into this supply zone again, we
wouldn't want to trust that for a trade
because it's already been hit. And
basically, what we're looking for is for
the supply zone to absorb all of the new
sell orders and drive lower like the one
we're currently looking at. We have
supply. The market has pulled back,
filled in balance. As soon as we hit
supply, we absorb all the selling
orders, new sell orders that come into
the market. We go and make a new low,
which means this supply zone is pretty
much redundant. Now the actions we would
then want to take would be to start
looking at you know the next imbalanced
supply zones for example maybe like this
one. But if the market was to return to
that supply zone again. So if we came up
to here we definitely wouldn't want to
look for another sell. Okay. The more
times a supply zone is hit even if it
doesn't break the first time the more
likely it is that soon it's going to
break through and actually go the other
way. So let's take a look what happens
next. Not 100% sure on this one, but we
can definitely take a look at that. We
can see that uh if the market comes up
to this level, we don't want to sell
there again because there is a high
likelihood as you can see there that the
market's going to go through it. So
although we had this supply zone prepped
up, we had the first trade which would
have been a great trade, but then the
second tap, we don't want to sell here.
This is not likely to get us into new
lows. As you can see, it didn't do that.
Third tap, we don't want to sell there.
Fourth tap, we don't want to sell there.
and then on the fifth tap it actually
breaks through. So a supply zone is only
really good for its first retest. Right
after that, ignore it. And the same goes
for demand. If we're in a buying
example, of course, we only want to use
the first tap of a demand zone, then we
move on to other zones to validate next
trades because the more times that
demand zone is rem, it's essentially
showing us that the buying pressure is
not strong in here anymore and it's
showing us sellers are really attempting
to push this lower and eventually they
will likely win. So crucial tips to
remember when trading supply and demand.
Always trade it in line with the trend.
Only trade imbalanced zones. So any
zones that aren't imbalanced or not
worth trading. And only trade the first
tap of a zone. If a zone has been hit
three, four, five times, do not trade
it. It will likely break. Okay, now that
we've covered all that, I want to talk
about different zones. So we're going to
talk about extreme zones first of all
and then how to approach multiple zones.
So this market is downtrending. Okay, we
had a breakup structure here. The market
has created a new lower low at this
price point. Say we want to sell this.
How are we going to select which zone to
sell from? First, we can follow the rule
of imbalance. We say we want to see
imbalances into a supply zone.
Otherwise, there is no uh reason to take
a trade from that point. If we take a
look anywhere pretty much from the top
of the movement down to here, we can see
there is no remaining imbalanced zones
inside of this price movement. So every
single one of these zones here has been
retested by a wick. There is no candle
where the wicks to wicks are not meeting
each other. Therefore there is no
imbalance. Okay. Now there was some
slight imbalance created here. But we
see that the market filled that range
and retested just here. So all imbalance
before this point is filled. There is no
imbalance ahead of this level. That's
going to lead us to look at this area
just here. And in here there are two
areas that we could look at as our trade
entry to sell. The first is this one at
the top, this indecision candle before
this impulsive move down. This is what
we call the extreme zone. Now an extreme
zone is simply the furthest zone from
price in the existing leg of movement.
So if there was an imbalance zone up
here being within this leg of movement
from the top down to the bottom, the
extreme zone would be whichever the
furthest one from where price currently
is is up here. However, there isn't any
imbalanced areas up here. So, the
furthest zone from price inside of this
existing leg of price action from this
point we're at now is going to be this
one that we've drawn the red arrow to
because this is the final imbalance
zone. Therefore, basically, if the
market gets past this, we can expect
because there's no real supply anywhere
in here that the market has a pretty
good likelihood of actually just moving
into new highs. Okay? So, if we're
looking for the highest probability
place to sell from, we can do that from
just here. Now, there is of course a
level just beneath as well, it's going
to be this little bit of indecision
before the continued selloff. Now, it's
not really the greatest supply zone. And
what we still have here is imbalance
above, which is pretty clear, which
leads us through to a pretty significant
point being that extreme zone. So in an
example like this, we would definitely
want to focus on this zone over this
zone. However, that's not to say that we
have to completely write off any
possibility of finding a position from
this lower zone. We could still maybe
see the market flip. So what we can do
inside of any zones when we have a
situation where there are multiple zones
is we can use what we call a standard
confirmation or a confirmation entry.
That's going to be a pattern like what
you see here, which is basically where
we're looking for a lower time frame
structural shift and then if the market
goes from creating higher highs and
higher lows inside of this existing
trend, for example, where we start here,
create a high, higher low, higher high.
If we trended up like this and then we
had a shift in this higher higher low
structure into a lower low here, then we
would use fractal supply zones to sell
again. then we could use this area a
supply zone inside of the smaller price
action here to actually get an execution
to take the market down. Okay. So if we
approach it this way basically if the
market confirms a reversal in here we
get a trade. If it doesn't confirm a
reversal so if the market just comes up
and goes straight through then because
we waited on that confirmation we
actually don't take a loss. We just
don't take any trade at all because it
hasn't confirmed. So the extreme zone is
the highest probability point to sell
from or buy from when it comes to supply
and demand. We would be happy in this
instance then to place a sell order in
the terms of a sell limit at this level.
If you're going to be placing sell
limits and buy limits, the best place to
do that is at extreme zones. And if
you're going to be approaching the
market with confirmation or you're
approaching a market that has multiple
potential zones, then you're going to
want to use confirmation on pretty much
all of them except the extreme zone.
Now, when we see the market come up into
this area, we do, however, get a
confirmation entry. And I want to walk
you through it now so you can see what
it looks like in the real market. So,
we're going to remove that for now, the
hypothetical sell limit idea. And we'll
take a look at this structure that we
have right here. We've hit the supply
zone just there, which gives us what we
want to see to have confidence and
clarity to start selling. Now, the
confirmation entry has actually arisen
inside of this price action. So if we
mark the low to the high to the low,
this is going to be our trending
structure right now. Okay, we then have
basically smaller trending price action
like that. This is the kind of trend
that we have. Okay, by marking the highs
and lows of this bullish movement, we're
then basically looking for this to shift
bearish to provide us confirmation to
sell into this market. Now, as we can
see then our swing lows or our higher
lows are going to be pretty much this
point here. And then a more significant
one will be this one here. Now, we can
see with this bearish candle, we've had
a closure beneath both of these lows.
So, what this actually does is allow us
to sell into this because we are seeing
with the formation of this lower low
that we've just got here, we are seeing
the market shifting to bearish, to a
selling setting. We're seeing it shift
to a downtrend, which agrees with the
high time frame narrative of, of course,
this bearish trend idea. So what we do
here by bringing this in is actually use
kind of the big picture and then a more
refined smaller picture to build a
scenario in the market where the high
and the low time frames are in complete
agreement. When we have that we can sell
with confidence because now we know the
high time frame is telling us the market
is bearish. The low time frame has also
now agreed and told us the market is
bearish. We actually use supply and
demand here in a fractal nature. So
fractal essentially means the same
patterns will form on all different time
frames. They will form in all different
scenarios regardless of whether you're
looking at the daily, the weekly,
regardless of whether you're looking at
the high time frame zoomed out price
action or the more refined zoomed in
price action. It's all going to work the
same. So the big picture trend, which is
going to be this one that we're looking
at, this is bearish and we have our
supply zone which we wanted to sell
from. Now the smaller picture trend
which is going to be this one here has
also now shifted bearish and what it's
done in doing so is provide us with a
supply zone to sell from. Right now the
supply zone in question here is the last
indecision candle before the impulse
away. Very simple stuff. That means we
can therefore place our sell limit on
this area target down into the low or
wherever we want this to go to. And for
this we don't have to put the stop over
this swing high because we have new
confirmations inside of this structure.
So, we can actually put our stop loss
over this high and that's going to
provide a very safe trade as well. But
this time, we have that kind of double
confirmation. We've had that shift
standard confirmation here. We've sold
on this retest here and now we'd be
looking for the market to roll over and
make a new low given that it's reacted
from supply once and then reacted from
the second supply providing two supply
reactions. And as you can see, that is
exactly what happens. So, in a general
market scenario, you want to focus
primarily on the extreme zone, which is
going to be the last imbalance candle in
this leg of price action. For this
scenario, it's this one here. If there
are other zones to focus on, such as
this one here, then the best way to
approach these, if you want to focus on
these zones at all, is to go in with the
standard confirmation, which, as you've
just seen, is actually what we've got
going on here. This pattern of shifting
from higher highs and higher lows into a
lower low and then pulling back and
selling from supply can be utilized not
only from the extreme zones but from
these smaller zones within. If you see
this pattern formulating in one of the
other zones in a scenario where there
are multiple supply zones to choose from
then that can give you the confirmation
you want in order to get into a trade
that is likely to win. But if there is
no confirmation such as there wasn't any
in this zone then you simply avoid
taking the trade. meaning in most cases
you're going to avoid taking a loss and
then you can take your trades
comfortably from the extreme zone or if
you really want to you can use that
confirmation from there anyway and that
a lot of the times is going to provide
you with a good entry to get in okay but
I just want to give you a warning
confirmation entries while they are very
very strong are not going to happen all
of the time if we take a look back at
the price action here okay I'll jump it
back just to show you at this point our
extreme zone was this candle here this
indecision candle
We had this big push to the downside. We
have no imbalances above. We have no
other zones left open. So our extreme
zone is the one that we are looking at
just here. If you were going to wait for
a confirmation from this zone, you would
then want to see the market pull in and
make a shift in structure like this that
would allow you to get into a trade.
However, as you will see and as you may
have already seen, there was no
confirmation given. In fact, the
confirmation for this trade is actually
going to be when the market returns all
the way to this supply. But this is
going to mean you're not able to profit
on this entire move down. You're gonna
have to wait for the pullback to get it.
So essentially that becomes a missed
opportunity. So you can avoid that from
happening if you focus on extreme zones.
As I say, sell and buy limits most of
the time are going to be good from
these. It's not always going to work.
Sometimes the market will flip on you.
But the riskreward you can get from
these. You know, if you sold this
extreme zone, stop above the zone target
down into, you know, wherever you wanted
it to go. You got potential 5% 6% 7%
trades coming in here, which means even
if this only won half of the time,
you're making a significant profit
overall due to the fact that every time
you risk $100, you're making $700 in
return, right? So they stack up from a
riskreward perspective. But that
confirmation entry is uh a really solid
way to number one, double confirm the
trades if you really feel like you need
it. So you know, getting in from around
this point after this market
confirmation has occurred. And number
two, you can use this if you're not
trading from the extreme zone. if you're
looking at a more refined zone as well.
So that is kind of how you differentiate
between multiple zones. The extreme zone
is always the highest probability, the
highest reward, the most favorable zone
to buy or sell from. But if there are
other areas that you might want to look
at, just go at it with that confirmation
perspective. As long as you wait for
that, you're going to get what you want,
you're going to have the confirmation,
you'll have the confidence and the
clarity to get into the trade. Now, just
to quickly show you what this looks like
from a bullish perspective, then we
would have instead a demand zone here.
Demand zone's retested. Market pushes
up. We get a bullish break of structure
this time. So the market pushes over
these lower highs and then pulling back.
We want to utilize the demand zone, the
last candle before the impulse that
broke the structure. That's where we're
going to be getting into a trade there.
You can trade that up to the next highs
or beyond if you want to. That is a
breakdown of extreme zones, confirmation
entries, and how to approach supply and
demand zones in real markets where
things aren't as clean as theory talk.
So hopefully that's valuable. Let's move
on. Now, something really cool about
supply and demand is that this is a
fractal theory. Fractal means that the
concept works on pretty much any time
frame you want to look at. Whether you
want to look at the weekly, the daily,
the 4 hour, the 5 minute, the 1 minute,
it's all the same. So, let's take a look
at some examples. I bet you couldn't
guess what time frame these three
different examples are from. Now,
obviously, they all look very similar.
The market follows price action
regardless. These are the monthly, the 1
week, and the 1 hour. No, I'm just
kidding. It's the hourly, the 4 hour,
and the one minute time frame. And I do
that to show you that really you are
never going to guess what time frame a
supply or demand zone is formed on just
by looking at it. Which is a great thing
because it means whether you're day
trading, swing trading, position
trading, scalping, these concepts will
work regardless of the time frame. So
don't worry, you don't have to use a
specific time frame to use supply and
demand. You can use it anywhere. All
right. So, one big thing that you should
bring into your trading is top-down
analysis, which is pretty much the idea
of using multiple different time frames
to work out where the market's going to
go. You go from the top down on the
weekly and daily to build narratives,
and you go to the lower time frames and
actually find setups. Supply and demand
can be used in this context and it can
be used for two things. First of all, it
can be used to identify target areas.
Second of all, it can be used to
identify where trades are likely to take
place from and lead into. So, we're
taking a look at an example here on
Euroad. We're on the weekly time frame.
As I've shown you with fractalss, it
doesn't really matter what kind of time
frames you're working on, but this is a
breakdown as to how you can take
advantage of the targets and entries and
building narratives on the high time
frames using supply and demand. Here on
the weekly, I've just marked out a
supply zone. I've just marked out a
demand zone. Because the weekly time
frame moves so slowly and it covers so
much ground, we're not really looking
for massive movements on a time frame
like this. What we're looking for is
generally to find areas the market could
lead into as targets and as trade
entries. So, if we build this picture,
supply and demand, we've now got a clear
range as maybe the market could go up to
here. If it did, and we got
confirmation, we could sell down to
here. Or maybe the market could go down
to here. And if it did, we would then
look for opportunity to buy up to here.
And these ranges being weekly ranges are
actually pretty big. So if we were to
look for a sell from here down to here,
we're looking at over 130 pips. That's a
pretty big range that you can trade
through. That will give you some very
big trades. And then the run from this
zone to this zone is actually 400 pips,
which again is a very big range that you
can find one very large or multiple
smaller trades within. Now, if we then
run this market forward, obviously it's
lower time frames where you'll actually
be doing the analysis, but you're going
to see that we actually do build
narratives and ideas here because number
one, clear imbalanced demand. Well, if
the market is showing weakness down to
this level, selling here would be a good
trade to look for. So, that's going to
be a position that you could profit
from. Number two, when the zone is
filled, we know the next likely move for
it to make is probably going to be a
drive to the upside. So you could start
looking for buying opportunities from
there given lower time frame
confirmations. Now let's say we get into
the point that we're at right now. We've
had again a break of structure where the
markets came and created a higher high.
We have our standard confirmation
pattern looking like this. And now we
would say we're looking for a long
position. So what do we do? Well, on the
weekly we would identify an area of
demand like so. And then on the lower
time frames, because we've now got this
high time frame narrative of pulling
back to here and buying, we could look
for opportunities to sell from where we
are throughout the week using lower time
frames, daily, 4 hour, and then when we
meet this area, we could start looking
for opportunities to buy. So, if you
build your high time frame narratives,
all you literally need to do is use very
simple ranges and very simple supply and
demand. And as you can see by how this
market is forming right now, it's going
to fit into your analysis. and going to
give you some very very good trading
opportunities. Number one, in the form
of sells down into demand zones or buys
up into supply zones as we saw here. But
number two, once the ranges are filled
and once these demand zones and supply
zones are hit, well then you've got
clear entry opportunities because you
understand the probability is that that
zone will hold and we will likely lead
through towards the next area with the
next movement in price action. Weekly
time frames and daily time frames for
building narratives with supply and
demand. Very strong stuff. super super
simple and very effective as well. You
can start to trade range to range using
the supply and demand format. It really
simplifies your high time frame analysis
and gives you biases to work with inside
of each week. So to lead on and
elaborate on one of the concepts we just
discussed there, this is the idea of
using supply and demand not only for
entries but also for targets. We've gone
to a completely polarizing opportunity.
We are looking at the twominut time
frame to highlight that supply and
demand works the same on every single
time frame that you look at. Okay, for
our setup like this, the opposing move
is basically going to be this push down,
right? Or in the real example here,
we're looking inside of here to find
areas of supply. Let's take a look from
the low then. Well, we have this one,
but this has been hit. This is
efficient. There is no reason to look at
this anymore. As we know, when the
market hits a supply zone or demand zone
more than once, it becomes essentially
useless. which is also good news by the
way for forecasting the strength of this
trade because the fact we've gotten back
into this supply zone again and traded
higher than we did previously and closed
higher than we even did when we formed
the supply zone tells us this is a
strong move. Okay, so they can actually
be used uh multiple retests on supply or
demand zones to indicate strength
against the zone which allows us to get
more clarity for trades like this one.
But obviously that then is going to
write off this supply. Well, then there
is no imbalanced supply zone here.
There's a supply zone here, but it was
filled with this wick. Okay? And then
there is an imbalance supply here, this
indecision candle before this impulse
down. So, we're going to follow the same
rule. We're going to mark out the low to
the high of that supply zone. And what
we are going to do, as we've done in
these previous examples, and as I've
showed you, we're going to cover the
high of the wick of the next candle as
well. So, that's our supply zone. So
now, yes, we could target the overall
high, but if the market wanted to slow
down inside of this supply, or if we
wanted the simplest and most probable
high probability trade that we can get,
well, then we could go with this as our
target, which would be a 1 to5
riskreward. The idea then being if we
get our fill, if the market's going to
reverse, it is very highly likely at
this point to at least get to this
supply zone before it reverses. And of
course, a supply zone is the highest
probable point for a reversal to take
place because this is indication that
sellers stepped in here before. So there
is therefore the kind of forecasted
potential that sellers could step in
here again. When they do that, what
happens? The market goes down. So if we
want the cleanest possible trades, we
can actually use supply and demand to
identify the highest probable points to
get in, but also the highest probable
points for sellers to step in against
our trade or the highest probable points
for reversals to take place. And then if
we simply trade within that range from
demand to supply as we are here, you
know, there is no imbalance supply
anywhere here. There is here. So there
is very high likelihood of us getting to
this point. But there is also a
reasonable likelihood that this is where
the market reverses. So by understanding
this we have a clean trading range. We
can be in at demand extreme zone no
imbalances left beneath high probability
entry and we can be out at supply
extreme zone high probability reversal
high probability exit. No imbalance
beneath this which creates a very high
probable range for us to push through.
Okay. Now I'm going to run this. You're
going to see what happens when the
supply is hit. We get a small push
through. Good sign to begin with but
then we have this pretty dramatic
sell-off. Okay. Now obviously in some
cases the market is going to drill
straight through those zones and take
you up towards your targets. But in some
of these cases we are going to get these
selling movements and this can lead us
back into new bearish moves. So if you
target from demand to supply or from
supply to demand, you're basically
setting yourself up with the most
simplified positions that you can
possibly take and you avoid getting
killed when the market does stuff like
this. Reverses on your trade after
getting very very close to the target.
You know, if you held this trade all the
way up here, well, you're going to miss
out on this entire move now because it's
all the way back down to entry. But if
you just focused on demand to supply
trading, number one, it's very simple.
It's very easy. Number two, you're going
to be out of these trades because the
market is highly likely to trade from
range to range. It's only when new
ranges are met that significant
reversals can take place, making this
the most simple way to use supply and
demand as targets and entries. So,
that's pretty much everything you need
to know about supply and demand. Now, if
you want to get results like these and
master supply and demand fast, head to
the link in the description and join my
trading academy. If you don't want to do
that, I have a free course called Seven
Steps to Profitable Trades, where I'm
going to help you to build systems,
simplify your trading, improve your
trades, and ultimately find success.
There is a link to that at the top of
the description as well. And if you
don't want to do either of those things,
watch this master class on market
structure. This is going to follow on
from what we've covered today in supply
and demand and help you to become a
masterful trader. So, thank you for
watching.